

Website



Software Engineer | Singapore | marxlow94@gmail.com

Marx Low

www.marx-low.com



Profile

linkedin.com/in/marx-low/medium.com/@marxlow



Driven final year Computer Science undergraduate with 1.5 years of experience of developing robust production code. Proven enthusiastic team-player and creative problem-solver.

Skills

Languages

Java, Javascript

Frontend

ReactJS, HTML & CSS

Backend

NodeJS, ExpressJS

Deployment

Docker, Heroku, Circleci

Database

MongoDB

Languages

English, Chinese

Work Experience

Software Engineer Intern – Agolo – New York

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018 | 6 months

- Significantly Improved "Progressive Web Apps" score of web app by 800% to 80 and reduced load speed by 900% to 5 seconds on slow 3G.
- Automated acceptance test of the engineering pipeline with modern browser automation and testing tools to achieve close to 100% test coverage.
- Led the full-stack development of a proof-of concept web application to be used for daily meetings with potential clients.

Main stack – Javascript, React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes

Backend Software Engineer Intern – Commandiv – New York

Aug 2017 - Jan 2018 | 6 months

- Integrated cryptocurrency trading into Commandiv's web application to become the first ever stock & cryptocurrency trading platform in the world. Featured in Forbes.
- Built, tested and managed backend infrastructure to handle thousands of daily stock and cryptocurrency market data.
- Built highly reliable and scalable live APIs for user actions with the market.

Main stack – Javascript, Node, Express, MongoDB, Heroku

Backend Software Engineer Intern – Trabble – Singapore

May 2017 - Jul 2017 | 3 months

 Greatly improved test coverage across Model-View-Controller layers from ~1% to 40%.

Main stack - C#, SQL

Projects



Education

Al Tetris Player – implemented with PSO

Art Praiser – Online Art marketplace

Menion – Mood diary mobile app

Bachelor of Computing (Honours) - National University of Singapore

May 2015 - Current

- Specialization: Artificial Intelligence and Parallel Programming
- Relevant Modules: Parallel Computing | Data Structures & Algorithms | Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Software Engineering
- NUS Overseas College, New York 2017-2018